[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aec", "question": "In \"Shallow Hal\", what real-life person hypnotizes Hal into seeing people as their inner beauty?", "answer": "Tony Robbins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f60", "question": "Which 1966 story, by Philip K. Dick, served as the basis for the 1990 movie \"Total Recall\"?", "answer": "We Can Remember It for You Wholesale", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58f566fa33a95c66dc4fe767", "question": "Who directed the 1941 film \"Citizen Kane\"?", "answer": "Orson Welles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7e9", "question": "What ape's name is Malay for \"old man of the forest\"?", "answer": "The orangutan's", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa81", "question": "In which US state is Mount Vernon?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad9e0fae748bb36357acdf1", "question": "What does VHS stand for?", "answer": "Video Home System", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f16", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Robert Downey and Eddie Izzard?", "answer": "Charlie Chaplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c63", "question": "Who directed the Indiana Jones movies released in the 1980s?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c90d22852800b05cac20f13", "question": "What are the names of the 5 Space Shuttle Orbiters used by NASA on manned spaceflight missions?", "answer": "Columbia, Challenger, Discovery, Atlantis, Endeavour", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a029", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", who did Peter force to become a professional boxer?", "answer": "Lois", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e18", "question": "What ship was commanded by Captain Corcoran?", "answer": "Pinafore", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb5bea5dad637d903c881c", "question": "Which country observes an official Vernal Equinox Day?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ded2ebea2747c8aff16d43", "question": "What is a device to stem the flow of blood called?", "answer": "A tourniquet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a09a", "question": "Elvis's manager, Colonel Tom Parker, had what earlier act?", "answer": "Dancing chickens", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b2", "question": "What is the heaviest breed of bear?", "answer": "Polar bear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4dd", "question": "What is the most mountainous country in Europe?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a544", "question": "Which US state is home to Clemson University?", "answer": "South Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a91420565ad31a57c7fc", "question": "What Dallas nightclub did Oswald murderer Jack Ruby own?", "answer": "The Carousel Club", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa55a3c73aa70ea0b70b24", "question": "Sahti is a type of beer that is traditionally flavored with juniper and it is most likely found in which country?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b255", "question": "What Ken Kesey-led group toured American in a psychedelic school bus called \"Further\"?", "answer": "The Merry Pranksters", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea7decff048f679a45ac02", "question": "Aphenphosmphobia is fear of what?", "answer": "Being touched", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a48", "question": "In the TV series, which one of the four main characters on \"Sex and the City\" had a baby?", "answer": "Miranda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be2c", "question": "The Chicago Bulls take the court to \"Sirius\", an instrumental track by what prog-rock band?", "answer": "The Alan Parsons Project", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9096c01dd7bf43be5e88f", "question": "Aphyllous trees lack what?", "answer": "Leaves", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339822", "question": "What American opera singer was nicknamed \"Bubbles\"?", "answer": "Beverly Sills", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe3eda68b5801b8f54a7fb4", "question": "Who did Barack Obama marry in 1992?", "answer": "Michelle Robinson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f3", "question": "What sport was once contested with a spadroon?", "answer": "Fencing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc1573469bb8041d07a08b", "question": "What London landmark did Queen Elizabeth II open up to tourism in 1993?", "answer": "Buckingham Palace", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a0", "question": "What movie starred Johnny Depp as Willy Wonka?", "answer": "Charlie and the Chocolate Factory", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7346aeec85e375820b234", "question": "How many future presidents signed the US Declaration of Independence?", "answer": "Two", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133930d", "question": "In the movie \"Rambo:First Blood\", how many people did John Rambo kill?", "answer": "One", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c01b", "question": "What three letter word means \"the front of a ship\"?", "answer": "Bow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0fd", "question": "What is a sternocleidomastoid?", "answer": "A muscle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d0cf2596a59cbdfbd381", "question": "Who first said, \"When you reach the end of your rope, tie a knot and hang on\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa420fc73aa70ea0b70b13", "question": "Father Damien ministered to lepers on which Hawaiian Island?", "answer": "Molokai", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feba92b7e83c707845b20d2", "question": "Sailors from years past suffered from scurvy due to a lack of what?", "answer": "Vitamin C", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c7", "question": "A silk-screened print is also known as what?", "answer": "Serigraph", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad6c", "question": "Which US president had a sign on his desk that read \"The Buck Stops Here\"?", "answer": "Harry Truman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2ff", "question": "What was the first man-made insecticide?", "answer": "DDT", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600cc34a6de0eb824d4052ec", "question": "Which city in the contiguous U.S. will lead you to Canada if you drive due south?", "answer": "Detroit -- From Detroit, drive south over the Ambassador Bridge across the Detroit River, and you\u2019ll hit Windsor, Ontario.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338945", "question": "Which great painter's nickname translated literally to \"The Greek\"?", "answer": "El Greco", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd6629fa5bfecdd737e0846", "question": "Who were Virginia and West Virginia named for?", "answer": "Queen Elizabeth I, the Virgin Queen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b62e", "question": "To which color group does St. Charles Place belong on a standard US Monopoly board?", "answer": "Light purple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af98549aeb0982ee455954d", "question": "Which video game released in 2017 has an animation style similar to the 1930\u2019s?", "answer": "Cuphead", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133936c", "question": "Who was originally cast as Marty in the movie \"Back To The Future\"?", "answer": "Eric Stoltz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b191", "question": "What year was Napoleon Bonaparte born?", "answer": "1769", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f34", "question": "Which band member of The Germs died of drug overdose?", "answer": "Darby Crash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a831", "question": "The powerful Inca empire had its capital seat at Cuzco in what modern-day South American country?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abbd", "question": "Where might you drink Retsina wine?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa6a", "question": "What is the International Calling Code for Australia?", "answer": "61", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b387", "question": "In which country was the first soccer World Cup held?", "answer": "Uruguay", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067c64ff9c0647b50a806b", "question": "What date were the opening ceremonies of the 2016 Summer Olympics held on?", "answer": "August 5, 2016", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59db75050ab2c8f322317fe3", "question": "On which coast would you find the smallest Canadian province?", "answer": "East coast", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede4a26ce05a3942286ddf", "question": "In 1994, Elton John wrote the songs for which Disney animated film with lyricist Tim Rice?", "answer": "\"The Lion King\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdab94a0b8cce1e6fda7054", "question": "Which person is known for publishing \"The Interpretation of Dreams\"?", "answer": "Sigmund Freud", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a27e", "question": "In which 1989 film did Kevin Costner play the role of Ray Kinsella?", "answer": "Field of Dreams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ab", "question": "What 1972 movie revolves around the happenings at the Kit-Kat Klub?", "answer": "Cabaret", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe937c36bd93ce3a4e5f676", "question": "Gamophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Marriage and commitment", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e9105bbd7247dfc0fa00314", "question": "What is the atomic number of the element Tantalum?", "answer": "73", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a9", "question": "Who considered founding a utopian art colony at Arles in France prior to his suicide?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4de5706d333868d34d713", "question": "The Peloponnesian War was fought between Athens and which other ancient Greek state?", "answer": "Sparta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febd6ec7e83c707845b216f", "question": "Tommy Williams was caught stealing what from a shop in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Television", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b955", "question": "What nickname was given to mafia boss Charlie Luciano?", "answer": "\"Lucky\" Luciano", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69ec220565ad31a57c787", "question": "Which First Lady was the first to hold a job after marriage?", "answer": "Abigail Powers Fillmore", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd971fd23c87fd04dd15e4f", "question": "During World War II, what famous company produced propaganda films for the U.S. government?", "answer": "Walt Disney Productions", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bfdfef3b668d7dfe168b5b2", "question": "In 1979 what did President Carter apologise to Australia about?", "answer": "Skylab falling on their country", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdc0c8b469bb8041d07a052", "question": "What is a light and fluffy pie filling made with stabilized gelatin and beaten egg whites called?", "answer": "Chiffon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a14", "question": "Where does Spanish rain fall, according to \"My Fair Lady\"?", "answer": "On the plain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4b0a49076251badbeac0", "question": "What was Dwight D. Eisenhower's major campaign slogan during the 1952 presidential election?", "answer": "\"I like Ike\" -- Ike was Eisenhower's nickname.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab2d", "question": "Suva is the capital of which Melanesian country?", "answer": "Fiji", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398d5", "question": "What musical is set at Rydell High?", "answer": "Grease", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600b88d91d8c1817608d53f8", "question": "Originally called pimento, what popular spice was first grown in Jamaica?", "answer": "Allspice -- It is a fruit from a tropical evergreen tree, that is dried and either sold as berries or ground up to make the spice.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba52", "question": "What black and white bird is the official state bird of Minnesota?", "answer": "Common Loon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b2", "question": "Who played the role of officer Williams in the TV series \"In The Heat of the Night\"?", "answer": "David Hart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec1", "question": "During which battle did the charge of the Light Brigade take place?", "answer": "Balaclava", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60062bfac9d816e292245c27", "question": "What artist is best known for a painting of his mother?", "answer": "James McNeil Whistler's most famous painting is \"Arrangement in Black and Grey No.1\".  It is commonly known \"Whistler's Mother\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b5e", "question": "How many lines are in a limerick?", "answer": "5", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b439", "question": "What year was Albert Einstein born in?", "answer": "1879", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd2", "question": "What TV show did \"The Facts of Life\" spin off from?", "answer": "Diff'rent Strokes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af88", "question": "What militant organization was founded in 1966 by Huey Newton and Bobby Seale?", "answer": "Black Panthers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133893e", "question": "What armless statue in the Louvre is described as \"the most famous work of art of the ancient Greek sculpture\"?", "answer": "Venus de Milo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4a5", "question": "In which country is the source of the river Danube?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f49", "question": "What writer is called \"el manco de Lepanto\" for his injury from a 1571 battle?", "answer": "Miguel de Cervantes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396a6", "question": "Who played the role of T.E. Lawrence in the 1962 movie \"Lawrence of Arabia\"?", "answer": "Peter O'Toole", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59d184923b17032616b590fa", "question": "The fisrt armed daylight bank robbery in the US is said to have occured in what year?", "answer": "1866", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a701", "question": "Which US state is home to the Inyo Mountains?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ce", "question": "Which one of your toes is also known as your \"hallux\"?", "answer": "Big toe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c5f3fbde8045e48466b3", "question": "A \"bloat\" refers to a group of what animal?", "answer": "Hippopotamus -- A group of hippos consist of 10 to 20 females, their young, and one male hippo.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab1990baab681b09292191", "question": "What year was NASCAR founded?", "answer": "1948", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8cc", "question": "What city is home to the eighty-eight storey Petronas Twin Towers?", "answer": "Kuala Lumpur", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be55", "question": "Who plays their home games in the so-called Dean Dome?", "answer": "The North Carolina Tar Heels", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a53", "question": "In the Golden Earring song \"Radar Love\", what country artist do they hear playing on the radio?", "answer": "Brenda Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59029fe7cad1ec93f27df765", "question": "What country does the cappuccino originate from?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a86a", "question": "Which Bay is located to the north of Spain?", "answer": "Bay of Biscay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc62", "question": "What is depicted on a traditional \"Jolly Roger\" flag?", "answer": "Skull and Crossbones", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397e1", "question": "Which main character dies in the 2014 movie \"The Amazing Spider-Man 2\"?", "answer": "Gwen Stacy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c934877e98cb977789f1", "question": "What is Africa's oldest continuous democracy?", "answer": "Botswana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba41", "question": "What sport did hall-of-famer Willie Mays play?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133934f", "question": "What famous ex-boyfriend of Jennifer Aniston once guest-starred on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Brad Pitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c970", "question": "What is an organism called that lives on or in a host animal?", "answer": "Parasite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ade", "question": "In 1996, what action star was named a \"sacred vessel\" of Tibetan Buddhism?", "answer": "Steven Seagal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a005", "question": "In what film is Bill Murray the author of the play \"Return to Love Canal\"?", "answer": "Tootsie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76f8deec85e375820b2eb", "question": "What is the longest river in Europe?", "answer": "Volga River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a449", "question": "In which city are the Petronas Towers located?", "answer": "Kuala Lumpur", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e1c", "question": "What famed object from mythology did the Venus de Milo hold in her now-missing left hand?", "answer": "The golden apple of Paris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b530e662d71a53650ff6", "question": "Writing for a newspaper, what did Edgar Allan Poe encourage his readers to do?", "answer": "Send him encoded messages.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a261", "question": "Which British group recorded the song \"The House of the Rising Sun\" in 1964?", "answer": "The Animals", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab22", "question": "Which African coast is Mozambique located on?", "answer": "East", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ab99d8f21a8909e5c332d41", "question": "Which playing card is known as the \"Devil's Bedpost\"?", "answer": "The Four of Clubs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a120", "question": "Which year did John Schlesinger receive an Academy Award for directing \"Midnight Cowboy\"?", "answer": "1970", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133906a", "question": "Which American poet also practiced medicine?", "answer": "Oliver Wendell Holmes Sr.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8b54e01dd7bf43be5e7ce", "question": "What are Bic pens named after?", "answer": "A version of the founder's name", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015f112fe83fe1f2a824c15", "question": "Which F-word is used for the delay of a Senate matter by debate or proceudral motions?", "answer": "Filibuster", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7e95fb24f84e0b9f9ffcd", "question": "Seretse Khama was the first President of which African country?", "answer": "Botswana", "category": "history"}, {"id": "595247c2736d4be723796b73", "question": "What is the name of Lady Antebellum\u2019s first #1 hit?", "answer": "\"I Run To You\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aadb", "question": "What is the capital of Croatia?\u00a0", "answer": "Zagreb\u00a0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b53a", "question": "In what State is it illegal to smoke from a pipe after sunset?", "answer": "Rhode Island", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff20ff931a458464a93c43a", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Nostromo\"?", "answer": "Robert Conrad", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133999f", "question": "In \"Back to the Future\", when Marty goes back in time, what does his mother think his first name is?", "answer": "Calvin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133979d", "question": "What movie put Queen's 1976 hit \"Bohemian Rhapsody\" back on the charts in 1992?", "answer": "Wayne's World", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9dc69e748bb36357acddd", "question": "What 21st-century US presidential candidate had a spouse who was president of two colleges?", "answer": "Bernie Sanders", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394be", "question": "In the original Star Trek series, what was Dr. McCoy's nickname?", "answer": "Bones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae22", "question": "What are the four permanent, non-US members of the United Nations Security Council?", "answer": "China, France, Russia, United Kingdom", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b116", "question": "Who was the second man to set foot on the moon?", "answer": "Edwin \"Buzz\" Aldrin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339574", "question": "In, Santa Baby by Madonna what kind of fur does she want him to slip under the tree?", "answer": "A sable", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b971", "question": "Which variations brought lasting fame for Sir Edward Elgar?", "answer": "Enigma Variations", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b35c", "question": "What is British politician William Hague's middle name?", "answer": "Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa0a", "question": "What is the capital of Suriname?", "answer": "Paramaribo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c420", "question": "How many moons does Mars have?", "answer": "Two", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59f9b990364247bf200fb88d", "question": "What is the fear of commitment known as?", "answer": "Gamophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6ad", "question": "What are the main ingredients of borscht?", "answer": "Beet roots and cabbage", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338996", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Terms of Endearment\" that was later adapted into a 1983 Best Picture film?", "answer": "Larry McMurtry", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a481", "question": "Which two small states are surrounded by Italy?", "answer": "San Marino and the Vatican City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a211", "question": "Who sang in a pop duo alongside Melanie Appleby?", "answer": "Kim Appleby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25f1156682715b82711cdc", "question": "Bristol, Rockingham, Chelsea, and Minton are types of what?", "answer": "Pottery porcelain China", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecdd21ec223966ae8f88ff", "question": "Who introduced Johnny Depp to acting?", "answer": "Nicolas Cage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59decf1dea2747c8aff16d1a", "question": "In horse racing how many Furlongs are in a mile?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe25a4e658e585fda9cfa45", "question": "What type of dog did Queen Elizabeth II of England call her favorite?", "answer": "Corgi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a57a", "question": "Coney Island is located on what island?", "answer": "Long Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338971", "question": "What sport was most frequently featured in Degas' paintings?", "answer": "Horseracing", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394f6", "question": "Which Teletubby has a triangle on its head?", "answer": "Tinky Winky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c78", "question": "Which movie introduced Indiana Jones to the public?", "answer": "Raiders of the Lost Ark", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1a5", "question": "Which sport awards the Sam Maguire Cup?", "answer": "Gaelic Football", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c7", "question": "Hurricane season in the North Atlantic officially begins on the first day of what month?", "answer": "June", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdc0c7a469bb8041d07a051", "question": "What is \"Ajiaco\"?", "answer": "A type of chicken soup", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6a6fe6c0f9723ab15cb59", "question": "What does \"A.D.\" stand for, in reference to dates?", "answer": "Anno Domini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133973a", "question": "Who composed the jazz classic \"I Got Rhythm\"?", "answer": "George Gershwin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0cc", "question": "What is the official name for the \"pound\" or \"number\" symbol on the telephone keypad?", "answer": "Octothorpe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e0d", "question": "What author wore a trademark dyed-green carnation in his lapel in 1890s London?", "answer": "Oscar Wilde", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58f5649133a95c66dc4fe74f", "question": "Roman Polanski directed which 1974 film starring Jack Nicholson?", "answer": "Chinatown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51ce2ff04d658268c931d", "question": "Who invented the rubber band?", "answer": "In 1845, Stephen Perry, of the rubber manufacturing company Messers Perry and Co., invented the rubber band.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa77", "question": "What is the capital of Malawi?", "answer": "Lilongwe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fc991d875534e0fe3fe3c2b", "question": "Who said, \"I don't like to pay for the same real estate twice\"?", "answer": "General George S Patton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "593c4a60b8198b9a2b07795b", "question": "Who played the male lead role in the film \"Terminator Salvation\"?", "answer": "Sam Worthington", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5be", "question": "Who is the inventor of Coca Cola?", "answer": "John Pemerton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ab1b20c4fda37788a9a1db6", "question": "Armagnac is a brandy originating from which area of France?", "answer": "Gascony", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a34b", "question": "Which African country was the setting for the TV serial \"The Flame Trees of Thika\"?", "answer": "Kenya", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133affa", "question": "What general led the Confederates at the Battle of Gettysburg?", "answer": "General Robert E. Lee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c774", "question": "What animal species name is slang for the mechanics profession?", "answer": "Monkeys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133889c", "question": "Who said: \"I've had such a curious dream\"?", "answer": "Alice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c25a", "question": "What is 400 in Roman numerals?", "answer": "CD", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399b6", "question": "The band Duran Duran took its name from a character in what Jane Fonda sci-fi movie?", "answer": "Barbarella", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067f4eff9c0647b50a8082", "question": "In October of 2016, just 2 months after its initial release, what product did Samsung stop manufacturing and selling?", "answer": "Galaxy Note 7", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca41", "question": "Gingivitis is inflammation of the what?", "answer": "Gums", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdffc9f1cf6db9ac4808d01", "question": "What is the smallest country located entirely within the Himalayas?", "answer": "Bhutan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe73482eec85e375820b236", "question": "Who was the first president to pardon a turkey?", "answer": "Harry Truman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fc2f837cee580c7f8fd1e60", "question": "What is the tallest mountain in the contiguous US?", "answer": "Mount Whitney", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339534", "question": "Who played the role of Larry Sanders on \"The Larry Sanders Show\"?", "answer": "Gary Shandling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062d9ac9d816e292245c34", "question": "Who painted \"The Scream\"?", "answer": "Edvard Munch\u00a0painted \"The Scream.\"  His style is recognized by most critics as leading to the birth of German Expressionism.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a30c", "question": "Who played the role of Marcy Runkle on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Pamela Adlon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bef6", "question": "Which Saint is said to have carried his own head for six miles after his death?", "answer": "Saint Denis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e38", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"Mrs. Whatsit\"?", "answer": "A Wrinkle in Time", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acc9", "question": "What was John F. Kennedy called by his friends?", "answer": "Jack", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bba2", "question": "Infantry, Cavalry, and Artillery cards are key to what Parker Brothers game?", "answer": "Risk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1e2", "question": "The band \"The Who\" were also known as \"The Detours\" and what other name?", "answer": "The High Numbers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a707", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Peach State\"?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5d1", "question": "What company makes Reese's Peanut Butter Cups?", "answer": "The Hershey Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ff", "question": "Which country were the 1988 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdab35e0b8cce1e6fda7045", "question": "Which nuts are used to make marzipan?", "answer": "Almonds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ae85e134007905755f79e86", "question": "In chronological order, what is the first book in the Chronicles of Narnia series?", "answer": "The Magician\u2019s Nephew", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133949b", "question": "What actor replaced Michael J. Fox as the deputy mayor on the TV show \"Spin City\"?", "answer": "Charlie Sheen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a25c", "question": "Which Hitchcock film starred Margaret Lockwood and Michael Redgrave?", "answer": "The Lady Vanishes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339de7", "question": "What 1971 film was partially set in the Korova Milk Bar?", "answer": "A Clockwork Orange", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fc5", "question": "What famous murders inspired Alfred Hitchcock's film \"Rope\"?", "answer": "The Leopold and Loeb killings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a84f", "question": "The Niagara Falls name is derived from an Iroquois word meaning what?", "answer": "Thunder", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefa6206ce05a3942286ecb", "question": "In which city does the film \"Home Alone 2\" take place?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca3a", "question": "Which element appears sixth on the periodic table?", "answer": "Carbon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338946", "question": "Which singer's 2000 autobiography \"Chasing Down the Dawn\" detailed her life growing up in Alaska?", "answer": "Jewel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c5dafbde8045e48466b1", "question": "An \"unkindness\" refers to a group of what animal?", "answer": "Ravens -- They have a bad reputation, and have been considered bad omens for centuries.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ae93fa574a5ce6b56b8241", "question": "In France, what would you buy in a Boulangerie?", "answer": "Bread", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339274", "question": "What is the fairy tale equivalent of Augustus in the show \"Once Upon A Time\"?", "answer": "Pinocchio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "596dfd319616e6c6d4eba4f4", "question": "What is a baby swan called?", "answer": "A Cygnet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c520", "question": "Polaris is commonly known as what star?", "answer": "The North Star", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c154", "question": "A Kamikaze cocktail contains vodka, triple sec and what?", "answer": "Lime juice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c20c877e98cb97778984", "question": "Where can you find \"Aphrodite's Rock\"?", "answer": "Cyprus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e1", "question": "What river separates Maryland and Virginia?", "answer": "Potomac River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe377f90ada16518afdc04e", "question": "Who was the founder of Cartier?", "answer": "Louis-Frantois Cartier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8bb", "question": "What nation's flag features a Sinhalese lion holding a sword?", "answer": "Sri Lanka", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d9b", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"The American President\"?", "answer": "Michael Douglas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa39a6ce05a3942286ea5", "question": "What was the name of the Today Show's chimpanzee mascot?", "answer": "J. Fred Muggs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a89890aac110e4167090", "question": "The Somersby cider brand is owned by which multinational brewing company?", "answer": "Carlsberg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc0", "question": "In Greek Mythology, what hung from an oak tree in the grove of Ares in Colchis, guarded by a dragon?", "answer": "The Golden Fleece", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e26", "question": "What did Benjamin Britten write the \"Young Person's Guide to\" in 1945?", "answer": "The Orchestra", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8d5", "question": "Which meteorological phenomena means \"a curl of hair\" in Latin?", "answer": "Cirrus clouds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339216", "question": "What fictional Kansas town is the earthly home of the young Superman?", "answer": "Smallville", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f78", "question": "Whose symphony number seven is called \"Leningrad\"?", "answer": "Dmitri Shostakovich's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdd5d260499cffc60b84231", "question": "A 1634 Spanish decree called what city \"Key to the New World and Rampart of the West Indies\"?", "answer": "Havana", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ae", "question": "In what city would you find Gorky Park?", "answer": "Moscow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e24", "question": "What kind of dinosaur is the Flintstones' Dino?", "answer": "A snorkasaurus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c419", "question": "What is a rhino horn made of?", "answer": "Keratin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "592eb0e5f83302ff91e464a1", "question": "Which luxury brand created a cellphone in 2009 containing more than 400 diamonds?", "answer": "Tiffany & Co.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af94", "question": "Who popularized the Christmas tree in England in the 19th century?", "answer": "Prince Albert", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f9e", "question": "Who wrote about Willie Wonka and the Chocolate Factory?", "answer": "Roald Dahl", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "592eb197f83302ff91e464a9", "question": "Which early 20th century actor was known as the \"Latin Lover\"?", "answer": "Rudolph Valentino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9a5", "question": "What volcano is the world's tallest mountain, when measured base to summit?", "answer": "Mauna Kea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fae", "question": "What nickname is shared by Charles Russell, Harold Reese, and Paul Reubens?", "answer": "Pee-Wee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cc7", "question": "Author J.M. Barrie is best known for creating what fictional character?", "answer": "Peter Pan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59f47342cfb6472aeed499d5", "question": "What is a \"Papoose\"?", "answer": "A Native American Child", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd81d04d0de9af39e9d468a", "question": "Why was 46 B.C.E. called the \"year of confusion\"?", "answer": "It had two extra months", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4ddaa06d333868d34d706", "question": "During World War II, where was \"Hacksaw Ridge\" located?", "answer": "Okinawa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5904998ccf93664eb1048692", "question": "Which famous actor is honored with a statue in Leicester Square?", "answer": "Charlie Chaplin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a47b", "question": "Which stretch of water is Europe's most northern boundary?", "answer": "Arctic Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a34", "question": "What movie western earned Gene Hackman his second acting Oscar?", "answer": "Unforgiven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd81c7dd0de9af39e9d4685", "question": "Where was the Liberty Bell hidden during the Revolutionary War?", "answer": "Allentown, Pennsylvania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa3af7c73aa70ea0b70ae3", "question": "What mountain range stretches from the town of Seesen in northwest Germany to Eisleben in the east?", "answer": "The Harz", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff259af31a458464a93c46e", "question": "If a person's candle flame goes off on the night of Halloween, it indicates that the person is with what?", "answer": "A ghost", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a1", "question": "Who is known as Slim Shady?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa56e2c73aa70ea0b70b2e", "question": "In Portugal, what object is traditionally thrown at friends in celebration of April Fool's Day?", "answer": "Flour (Flour bombing' is an established April Fool's Day practice in Portugal and some other countries.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ea", "question": "The music band \"The Cardigans\" hail from what European country?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4da", "question": "What fruit comes in Navel and Blood variety?", "answer": "Oranges", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febda007e83c707845b2180", "question": "In 2009, which artist set the record for the longest leap to number-one in Billboard Hot 100 history?", "answer": "Kelly Clarkson's 2009 hit \"My Life Would Suck Without You\" jumped from number-97 to number-1 in the course of a week.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febafbe7e83c707845b20ff", "question": "What causes the phenomenon of red \"watermelon snow\"?", "answer": "Algae", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c157", "question": "Which three ingredients does a Kamikaze cocktail contain?", "answer": "Vodka, triple sec and lime juice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bd1", "question": "Which ABBA song won the 1974 Eurovision Song Contest?", "answer": "Waterloo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ea9", "question": "In what comic strip would you find siblings Clayton, Katy and Nick?", "answer": "Adam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bb35ac72627b8fe95581be9", "question": "In what country was Mel Gibson born?", "answer": "United States", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b36f751c3f17ccc40c8e0e", "question": "In the film \"The Sixth Sense\", what does Cole find in the box Kyra directed him to?", "answer": "A videotape", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d54", "question": "What year saw the release of the first Harry Potter book?", "answer": "1997", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6d4", "question": "Which US state has the most shoreline along the Pacific Ocean?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7667deec85e375820b281", "question": "In what country would you celebrate \"Carnival\"?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339feb", "question": "Queen and Duran Duran both had drummers with what name?", "answer": "Roger Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a43e6c0f9723ab15cb52", "question": "When did Mormons first settle in Utah?", "answer": "1847", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa56", "question": "What is the capital of the Canadian Province of Quebec?", "answer": "Quebec City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5990f916fa5fdd6dd25324f4", "question": "Dendrochronology is better known as what?", "answer": "Ring dating", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b8", "question": "Which novel is the movie \"Blade Runner\" loosely based on?", "answer": "Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c403", "question": "What color is soapstone when it is first mined?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59008f4fcf842fa4c4ba96ba", "question": "Who released the 1970 album \"After the Gold Rush\"?", "answer": "Neil Young", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b498", "question": "What year were the Olympic Games hosted in the US for the first time?", "answer": "1904", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4be", "question": "When did the Seychelles gain their independence from the United Kingdom?", "answer": "June 29, 1975", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b5c", "question": "Who played Babe Ruth in the 1992 film \"The Babe\"?", "answer": "John Goodman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff144b6b0ee8c595b6d39b7", "question": "What is the first book in Dan Brown's \"Robert Langdon\" series?", "answer": "\"Angels and Demons\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a6", "question": "What plant does the Boll Weevil destroy?", "answer": "Cotton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaaa", "question": "What is the capital of Turkey?", "answer": "Ankara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b3c", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Gone with the Wind\"?", "answer": "Margaret Mitchell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133988a", "question": "What instrument is Questlove most famous for playing?", "answer": "Drums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7f6", "question": "What sea lies between Greece and Turkey?", "answer": "Aegean Sea", "category": "geography"}]